<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Students on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/students/</link><description>Recent content in Students on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Great people meet at La Sorbonne</title><link>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I posted the pictures of the Imagine Cup conference that took place in Paris and during which I had the opportunity to interview Bill Gates.
An event like that was of course filmed and now the videos are also available for online viewing and for download from the web site of Microsoft France.
There are six videos:
French (well, French and Costa Rican :P) finalists from 2007 (French) Bernard Charlès, CEO Dassault Systèmes (French) Ora Ito, Designer (French) Andrew Herbert, Microsoft Research Cambridge (English) Bill Gates, Microsoft Chairman (English) Q&amp;amp;A with Bill Gates (you can see me here again) (English) Click on &amp;ldquo;Voir &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to view the video online or &amp;ldquo;Télécharger&amp;rdquo; to download.</description></item><item><title>Photos with BillG</title><link>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 12:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</guid><description>As usual these days, there were all sorts of cameras present at yesterday&amp;rsquo;s activity. This is great because I of course couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my own pictures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a selection of pictures that I have received:
Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s me, to his left first and then to his right.
And here are links I&amp;rsquo;ve received/found with pictures of the event. I&amp;rsquo;ll be editing these as I find/get new ones:
G-IT Photos by Séverin Ferrand Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Emmanuel de Taillac Photos by Maxime Gaillard Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Johanna Piou</description></item><item><title>Nothing on TV? Switch to Channel 8!</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know when this went online because I&amp;rsquo;ve been mostly disconnected lately, with the moving and all, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep up with the blogosphere, but still I would like to present you a new Microsoft site.
First, do you know about Channel 9 and Channel 10?
Channel 9 was one of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s first initiatives to open up to the general public. Today it&amp;rsquo;s a website where developers, IT pros and other geeks can learn everything about past, present and future Microsoft technologies via videos, forums, blogs, etc.</description></item><item><title>¿Nada en la tele? ¡Ponga Channel 8!</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-es/</guid><description>No sé hace cuánto se lanzó porque he estado bastante desconectado últimamente, con la mudanza y todo, así que no he podido seguir de cerca la blogosfera, pero igual quisiera presentarles un nuevo sitio de Microsoft.
Pero primero, ¿ya conocen Channel 9 y Channel 10?
Channel 9 fue una de las primeras iniciativas de Microsoft para abrirse más hacia el público general. Hoy es un sitio donde desarrolladores, IT pros y otros geeks pueden aprender todo sobre las tecnologías Microsoft pasadas, presentes y futuras vía vídeos, foros, blogs, etc.</description></item><item><title>Rien à la télé ? Zappez sur Channel 8 !</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-fr/</guid><description>Je ne sais pas vraiment quand ça a été lancé parce que j&amp;rsquo;ai été assez déconnecté ces derniers temps, avec le déménagement et tout, du coup je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas trop suivi la blogosphère, mais je voudrais quand même vous présenter un nouveau site Microsoft.
Tout d&amp;rsquo;abord, connaissez-vous Channel 9 et Channel 10 ?
Channel 9 a été l&amp;rsquo;une des premières initiatives de Microsoft pour s&amp;rsquo;ouvrir au grand public. Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui c&amp;rsquo;est un site où les développeurs, IT pros et autres geeks peuvent tout apprendre à propos des technologies Microsoft passées, présentes et futures à travers des vidéos, forums, blogs, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>