<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Live Search on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/live-search/</link><description>Recent content in Live Search on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 04:23:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/live-search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why is Google better than Live Search?</title><link>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 04:23:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search/</guid><description>One word: relevance.
I was looking for information on WPF/e (now Silverlight) today and, without thinking twice, I went to Google to find it. However, after seeing how good the results were for this Microsoft technology, I thought I go take a look at the Redmond-giant’s own search engine and see how it performed.
Disappointing, to say the least.
Take a look at the results (I’m shrinking them to put them side by side, but you can click to see them better):</description></item><item><title>Pourquoi Google est meilleur que Live Search ?</title><link>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 04:08:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search-fr/</guid><description>Un mot : pertinence.
Je cherchais des informations sur WPF/e (désormais Silverlight) aujourd’hui et, sans y réfléchir deux fois, je suis allé les trouver sur Google. Cependant, après avoir vu combien les résultats de cette recherche d’une technologie Microsoft étaient excellents, je me suis dit que j’irais voir ce que ça donnait du côté du moteur de recherche du géant de Redmond.
Décevant, pour ne pas dire autre chose.
Regardez les résultats (j’ai réduit les images pour les mettre côte à côte, mais vous pouvez cliquer pour les voir en grand) :</description></item><item><title>¿Por qué Google es mejor que Live Search?</title><link>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 04:08:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/04/18/why-is-google-better-than-live-search-es/</guid><description>Una palabra: pertinencia.
Hoy estaba buscando información sobre WPF/e (ahora Silverlight) y, sin pensarlo dos veces, fui a Google para encontrarla. Sin embargo, después de ver que tan buenos fueron los resultados de la búsqueda de esta tecnología Microsoft, decidí darme una vuelta por el motor del gigante de Redmond para comparar.
Decepcionante, cuanto mucho.
Vean los resultados (reduje las imágenes para ponerlas a la par, pero se puede hacer clic para verlas mejor):</description></item></channel></rss>