<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 21:32:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Buscar un asterisco en Excel</title><link>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel-es/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 21:32:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel-es/</guid><description>El otro día estaba sentado en mi escritorio cuando, de pronto, alguien entró en la oficina e hizo la pregunta más extraña:
Estamos trabajando en Excel y hay una columna de números de orden con una estrella al final y quisiéramos borrarla. ¿Alguien sabe cómo hacerlo?
Obviamente, todos respondimos en coro:
¡Pues, Ctrl+H (o Edición &amp;gt; Remplazar) y remplaza el carácter ‘*’ por nada!
Excepto que, por supuesto, no funcionó.</description></item><item><title>Finding an Asterisk in Excel</title><link>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 21:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel/</guid><description>I was sitting at my desk when, suddenly, someone came in the office and asked the weirdest question:
We’re working on Excel and there’s a column with order number that end with a star and we’d like to remove it. Does anyone know how?
Obviously, we all immediately responded in choir:
Why, Ctrl+H (or Edit &amp;gt; Replace) and you replace character ‘*’ with nothing!
Except that, obviously, it didn’t work.</description></item><item><title>Rechercher un astérisque sous Excel</title><link>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel-fr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 21:32:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/11/finding-an-asterisk-in-excel-fr/</guid><description>J’étais assis à ma place quand, soudain, quelqu’un rentre dans le bureau de l’informatique avec la question la plus étrange :
On est sur Excel et on a une colonne avec numéros de commande qui se finissent tous par une étoile et on aimerait la virer. Quelqu’un sait comment on fait ?
Évidemment, la réponse en chœur a été immédiate :
Ben, Ctrl+H (ou Edition &amp;gt; Rechercher) et tu remplaces le caractère ‘*’ par rien du tout !</description></item><item><title>“The Art &amp;amp; Science Of CSS” FREE Download through Twitter</title><link>/2008/11/27/ldquothe-art-amp-science-of-cssrdquo-free-download-through-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 16:13:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/27/ldquothe-art-amp-science-of-cssrdquo-free-download-through-twitter/</guid><description>Sitepoint is giving away its book The Art &amp;amp; Science of CSS during a two-week “Twitaway” (5 days left as of the writing of this post).
The book looks pretty interesting from what I browsed when I got it a few minutes ago, so I actually recommend it at least as a quick reference for some pretty useful CSS techniques.
What do you have to do to get it? This is where it gets interesting:</description></item><item><title>Opening twhirl Links in Google Chrome</title><link>/2008/11/06/opening-twhirl-links-in-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 10:41:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/06/opening-twhirl-links-in-google-chrome/</guid><description>In spite of its bugs, I’ve been using Google Chrome as my main browser for a while now; mainly because it is generally fast and because it allows me to kill Flash whenever it bugs (often) without having to kill the whole browser.
I also use Windows Vista because I like it and it doesn’t feel slower than XP even on my computer.
Finally, I use twhirl to follow my Twitter friends.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Sysinternals Tools Has Never Been Easiser</title><link>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 06:46:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser/</guid><description>Do you know the Sysinternals tools?
You probably do if you&amp;rsquo;re an IT pro or a developer. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a series of free utilities written by Mark Russinovich that are essential to manage, troubleshoot and diagnose your Windows systems and applications. I even need one of the Sysinternals tools for my classes: ZoomIt allows you to zoom and draw on the screen.
Microsoft acquired Sysinternals some time ago and since then the tools have been available, always for free of course, from the TechNet website.</description></item><item><title>Acceder a las herramientas Sysinternals nunca fue tan fácil</title><link>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser-es/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 06:46:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser-es/</guid><description>¿Conocen las herramientas Sysinternals?
Probablemente sea el caso si son profesionales de la informática o desarrolladores. Para aquellos que no conocen, se trata de una serie de herramientas gratis escritas por Mark Russinovich que son esenciales para administrar, diagnosticar y reparar sus sistemas y aplicaciones Windows. Yo inclusive necesito una de las herramientas Sysinternals para mis clases: ZoomIt permite magnificar y dibujar en la pantalla.
Microsoft adquirió Sysinternals hace un tiempo y desde entonces los programas han estado disponibles, gratis por supuesto, en la página de TechNet.</description></item><item><title>Ça n'a jamais été aussi facile d'accéder aux outils Sysinternals</title><link>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser-fr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 06:46:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/31/accessing-sysinternals-tools-has-never-been-easiser-fr/</guid><description>Connaissez-vous les outils Sysinternals ?
C&amp;rsquo;est probablement le cas si vous êtes professionel de l&amp;rsquo;informatique ou développeur. Pour ceux qui ne connaissent pas, il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une série d&amp;rsquo;utilitaires gratuits écrits par Mark Russinovich qui sont indispensables pour gérer, dépanner et diagnostiquer vos systèmes et applications Windows. J&amp;rsquo;ai même besoin de l&amp;rsquo;un des outils Sysinternals pour mes cours : ZoomIt vous permet de zoomer et de dessiner à l&amp;rsquo;écran.
Microsoft a racheté Sysinternals il y a quelque temps et depuis les outils ont été disponibles, toujours gratuitement bien sûr, sur le site TechNet.</description></item><item><title>No todos sus e-mails son para usted</title><link>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you-es/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you-es/</guid><description>¡Exacto! No todo lo que llega a su bandeja de entrada es para uno y, por lo tanto, no merece su entera y, sobre todo, inmediata atención.
¿Entonces, qué hace todo ese correo ahí en primer lugar? Básicamente, hay tres tipos de e-mail:
están los e-mails que nos mandan esperando una acción y/o una respuesta de nuestra parte; están los e-mails que recibimos porque alguien quiere mantenernos al tanto ya sea mandándonos un e-mail directamente (o sea, nuestro nombre aparece en el campo Para) o poniéndonos en Cc; y para terminar, están los e-mails que llegan a nuestra bandeja pero que no nos conciernen directamente.</description></item><item><title>Tous vos mails ne sont pas à vous</title><link>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you-fr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 18:15:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you-fr/</guid><description>C&amp;rsquo;est exact ! Tout ce qui arrive dans votre boîte de réception ne vous est pas forcément destiné et, donc, ne mérite pas votre attention absolue et, surtout pas, immédiate.
Alors, que fait tout ce courrier dans votre boîte de réception ? Il y a différents types d&amp;rsquo;e-mails :
il y a les mails que l&amp;rsquo;on vous envoie en attendant une action ou une réponse de votre part ; il y a les mails que vous recevez parce que l&amp;rsquo;on veut vous maintenir informé soit en vous envoyant le mail directement (votre adresse se trouve dans le champ À) ou en vous mettant en Cc ; et enfin il y a les mails qui arrivent dans votre boîte mais qui ne vous concernent pas directement.</description></item><item><title>All your e-mail is not for you</title><link>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 18:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/19/all-your-email-is-not-for-you/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s right! Not everything that reaches your inbox is actually for you and, therefore, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve your full, and especially not your immediate, attention.
So, what is all this mail doing in your inbox in the first place? There are different types of e-mails:
there&amp;rsquo;s the e-mail that someone sent you expecting action and/or a reply from you; there&amp;rsquo;s the e-mail that you receive because someone wants to keep you in the loop either by sending you the e-mail directly (i.</description></item></channel></rss>