<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fun on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/categories/fun/</link><description>Recent content in Fun on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 16:36:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Révéler les données d’une bande magnétique à l’aide de rouille</title><link>/2010/05/09/reacuteveacuteler-les-donneacutees-drsquoune-bande-magneacutetique-agrave-lrsquoaide-de-rouille/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 16:36:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/09/reacuteveacuteler-les-donneacutees-drsquoune-bande-magneacutetique-agrave-lrsquoaide-de-rouille/</guid><description>Je suis tombé sur cet article chez BoingBoing il y a quelques minutes qui décrit comment révéler les données stockées dans une bande magnétique—comme celles que l’on trouve derrière les cartes de crédit—à l’aide de la rouille (l’oxyde de fer, hein, pas la sauce) en poudre. Comme ça avait l’air sympa, je me suis dit que je reproduirais bien l’expérience à la maison.
Je suis donc allé chercher mon morceau d’acier rouillé (n’importe quel métal ferreux devrait marcher) et un morceau de papier de verre—j’avoue que parfois je m’étonne de ce que je garde dans mon petit 35m2—et j’ai procédé à la confection de rouille en poudre très fine.</description></item><item><title>Valse Irritation d'après Nokia et la découverte de The EG</title><link>/2010/01/13/valse-irritation-dapregraves-nokia-et-la-deacutecouverte-de-the-eg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 05:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/13/valse-irritation-dapregraves-nokia-et-la-deacutecouverte-de-the-eg/</guid><description>Je découvre ce matin cette composition pour piano, qui date apparemment de quelques années, écrire à partir de la traditionnelle sonnerie Nokia par le pianiste québécois Marc-André Hamelin.
Plus intéressant peut-être que ce morceau, je découvre la conférence The EG—The Entertainment Gathering. Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une conférence à la TED. D&amp;rsquo;ailleurs, certaines des conférences sont carrément disponibles sur le site TED. Cette conférence est cependant plus orientée divertissement ou loisir, son but étant de redéfinir la manière dont on entretient nos idées (de l&amp;rsquo;anglais entertain ideas).</description></item><item><title>And the prize for best writing goes to…</title><link>/2009/08/12/and-the-prize-for-best-writing-goes-tohellip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 08:22:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/12/and-the-prize-for-best-writing-goes-tohellip/</guid><description>…Adobe! For this magnificent dialog box in its ubiquitous Adobe Reader.
The best part is that I couldn’t even open the PDF I wanted to open, and I’ll never know why :P
Comments: Beedoo - Aug 3, 2009
I have the same :) It occurs when you open a pdf file through IE on Windows 7 ? If yes, try to download it and open it :)
Qu&amp;rsquo;importe le navigateur, cela le fait également sous Chrome.</description></item><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog/</guid><description>This famous phrase has been used for a long time by typesetters, typographers and other professionals that need to use all 26 letters of the English alphabet. Today, courtesy of YouTube, I give you the illustrated version:
[Via Rocketboom]</description></item><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-es/</guid><description>Esta famose frase (en inglés por lo menos) ha sido utilisada desde hace mucho tiempo por tipógrafos, grafistas y otros profesionales que necesitan utilizar las 26 letras del alfabeto inglés. Hoy, gracias a YouTube, les propongo la versión ilustrada en video:
_LVo_aTo
[Via Rocketboom]
Comments: map quest.com charleston sc - Aug 1, 2014
The convenience of these machines is hard to match. People who love to cook prefer to have gadgets that will make your life easier in the kitchen.</description></item><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-fr/</guid><description>Cette phrase mythique (en anglais en tout cas) est utilisée depuis longtemps par des typographes, des graphistes et d’autres professionnels qui ont besoin d’utiliser toutes les 26 lettres de l’alphabet anglais. Aujourd’hui, grâce à YouTube, je vous propose la version illustrée en vidéo :
[Via Rocketboom]</description></item><item><title>If my kids turn out like this…</title><link>/2009/03/10/if-my-kids-turn-out-like-thishellip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 10:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/10/if-my-kids-turn-out-like-thishellip/</guid><description>[youtube As funny and cute as this little girl talking about Visual Studio 2008 might be, I’d be really, really scared if my kids turned out like this :P (that is, assuming anyone would actually dare have kids with me in the first place).
Oh, and did she actually test the WPF designer and XAML Intellisense? All the rest, I pretty much agree, but I’m really looking forward to better WPF and XAML support in VS 2010 ;)</description></item><item><title>The Simpsons visit the Mapple Store</title><link>/2008/12/01/the-simpsons-visit-the-mapple-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 10:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/12/01/the-simpsons-visit-the-mapple-store/</guid><description>In the latest Simpsons episode, the family visits the new Mapple Store at the mall.
I don’t know how long the video will stay online, but it’s just great!
I had never visited an Apple Store before my trip to London at the beginning of the month, but I found it was really fun; it felt like visiting the HQ of the Church of Scientology for some reason :P
Anyway, enjoy the fist few minutes of perfect Simpsons sarcasm.</description></item><item><title>Uno de los mejores fracasos de traducción</title><link>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever-es/</guid><description>Este nos llega directo del país de Gales, gracias à la BBC.
Parece una señal vial totalmente inocente, y lo es, en inglés. El problema es que en Gales todas las señales tienen que estar en el idioma local y para eso se necesita un traductor. Desafortunadamente, cuando se consultó para esta señal, el traductor no estaba en su oficina y lo que se usó como traducción fue la respuesta automática de su e-mail.</description></item><item><title>One of the Best Translation Failures, Ever</title><link>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 09:43:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever/</guid><description>This one comes straight from Wales, through the BBC.
It looks like an innocent street sign, and it is, in English. The problem is that in Wales all street signs must also be displayed in the local language and for that you need a translator. Unfortunately, when consulted for this sign, the translator was out of his office and his automatic reply was used as the actual translation. This is (more or less) what the sign actually says:</description></item><item><title>L’un des meilleurs échecs de traduction</title><link>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 09:43:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/05/one-of-the-best-translation-failures-ever-fr/</guid><description>Celle-ci arrive tout droit du pays de Galles grâce à BBC.
Cela ressemble à un panneau routier tout à fait innocent, et ça l’est, en anglais. Le problème c’est qu’au pays de Galles tous les panneaux doivent être écrits aussi dans la langue locale et pour cela il faut un traducteur. Malheureusement, quand on l’a consulté pour ce panneau, le traducteur n’était pas dans son bureau et c’est sa réponse automatique qui a été utilisée en tant que traduction.</description></item><item><title>Perfectamente tonto</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-es/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-es/</guid><description>¡Hay errores que son simplemente demasiado perfectos!
El texto en rojo se traduciría “Perfectamente tonto” en español.
Yo nada digo: Perfecto!</description></item><item><title>Parfaitement con</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-fr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-fr/</guid><description>Il y a des coquilles qui sont juste trop belles !
Pas besoin de traduire dans cette version, c’est juste beau comme ça.
Je vais me limiter à dire : Parfait !</description></item><item><title>Perfectly dumb</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb/</guid><description>Some typos are just beautiful!
The highlighted text would read “Perfectly dumb” or maybe even “Perfectly stupid” in English.
I’ll just say: Perfect!</description></item><item><title>Máquina de escribir a punto de hacerse USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-es/</guid><description>Hace un rato compré una máquina de escribir (la de la foto) con única intención de, algún día, conectarla a mi computadora con un cable USB. Por supuesto, yo sé que una máquina de escribir sería un teclado muy ruidoso, pero a quién le importa? :P
También sé que, obviamente, otros lo han hecho antes, pero una vez más, a quién le importa?
El primer paso fue comprar la máquina de escribir.</description></item><item><title>Machine à écrire sur le point de devenir USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-fr/</guid><description>Il y a un moment j&amp;rsquo;ai acheté une machine à écrire (celle de la photo) avec l&amp;rsquo;intention d&amp;rsquo;un jour pouvoir la brancher sur mon ordinateur en USB. Oui, je sais, une machine à écrire fait un clavier très bruyant, mais on s&amp;rsquo;en fout, non? :P
Je ne suis évidemment pas la première personne à le faire, mais encore une fois, on s&amp;rsquo;en fout, non?
Alors, la première étape était d&amp;rsquo;acheter la machine à écrire.</description></item><item><title>Typewriter soon to be USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb/</guid><description>A while ago I bought a typewriter (the one in the picture) with the intention of one day being able to connect it to the computer using a USB cable. Sure, a typewriter will make for a noisy keyboard, but who cares? :P
I&amp;rsquo;m obviously not the first one to do it, but again, who cares?
So, the first step was buying the typewriter. Thanks to eBay that&amp;rsquo;s done. And, if you look carefully, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the keyboard&amp;rsquo;s layout is almost like my Swiss French layout that I like so much.</description></item><item><title>Does this thing have a manual?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual/</guid><description>Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think an escalator needed one, but the numbers seem to say different:
For those who can&amp;rsquo;t read the poor quality text, it says &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;.
The number drew my attention for two reasons:
What are the probabilities of the number of injuries on escalators being a power of 2? How can there be almost 3 injuries per day on something as trivial as an escalator? (that&amp;rsquo;s an interrobang, in case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering) Sure, the escalators on the London tube can be impressive:</description></item><item><title>Y a un manuel utilisateur pour ce machin ?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-fr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-fr/</guid><description>Je ne pensais pas qu&amp;rsquo;un escalator en aurait besoin, mais les chiffres semblent indiquer le contraire :
Pour ceux qui n&amp;rsquo;arrivent pas à lire le texte, c&amp;rsquo;est marqué &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;, c&amp;rsquo;est-à-dire &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;an dernier : 1024 blessés&amp;rdquo;.
Le chiffre a attiré mon attention pour deux raisons :
Quelles sont les probabilités que le nombre de blessés dans un escalator soit une puissance de 2 ? Comment peut-il y avoir presque 3 blessés par jour dans quelque chose d&amp;rsquo;aussi trivial qu&amp;rsquo;un escalator ?</description></item><item><title>¿Hay un manual para esta cosa?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-es/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-es/</guid><description>Pues, nunca pensé que una escalera eléctrica necesitara uno, pero las cifras indican lo contrario:
Para los que no logran leer el texto, dice &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;, o sea &amp;ldquo;El año pasado: 1024 heridos&amp;rdquo;.
El número me llamó la atención por dos razones:
¿Cuáles son las probabilidades de que el número de heridos en escaleras eléctricas sea una potencia de 2? ¿Cómo puede haber casi 3 heridos por día en algo tan trivial como una escalera eléctrica?</description></item><item><title>The Devil Wears Prada to the next Live Meeting</title><link>/2007/12/25/the-devil-wears-prada-to-the-next-live-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 20:36:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/25/the-devil-wears-prada-to-the-next-live-meeting/</guid><description>For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the same routing on Christmas day:
Wake up, unwrap presents, have breakfast, watch a movie, visit relatives.
Of course, over time, things have changed slightly. Most notably, the time I wake up, that fact most presents are actually opened the night before, breakfast became brunch and most of my relatives now live a 14-hour flight away.
Movie time didn&amp;rsquo;t change, though, and today&amp;rsquo;s was The Devil Wears Prada.</description></item><item><title>Countdown to WPF</title><link>/2007/09/11/countdown-to-wpf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 20:36:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/09/11/countdown-to-wpf/</guid><description>Back in January 2006, when Microsoft was preparing to release the .NET Framework 2.0 and, with it, the Windows Presentation Foundation, countdowns seemed to pop up everywhere:
Dazzling Graphics: Top Ten UI Development Breakthroughs In Windows Presentation Foundation</description></item><item><title>How many countries can you name in 10 minutes?</title><link>/2007/03/07/how-many-countries-can-you-name-in-10-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 21:59:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/03/07/how-many-countries-can-you-name-in-10-minutes/</guid><description>I got to 81 while teaching (yes, I know I shouldn’t play in class…)
I might have guessed more if I had been doing only that and if it were more flexible with spelling (”The Bahamas” is not the same as “Bahamas” for example).
How many can you do?</description></item><item><title>Interesting Google search results</title><link>/2006/11/13/interesting-google-search-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 23:08:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/13/interesting-google-search-results/</guid><description>Have fun:</description></item><item><title>Résultats intéressants de recherches sur Google</title><link>/2006/11/13/interesting-google-search-results-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 23:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/13/interesting-google-search-results-fr/</guid><description>Amusez-vous bien :</description></item><item><title>Le meilleur navigateur sur le marché</title><link>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there-fr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 13:51:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there-fr/</guid><description>Si vous lisez ce blog vous avez probablement déjà téléchargé et installé la toute dernière version d’Internet Explorer et/ou Firefox et arbitrairement choisi votre camp dans la Guerre des navigateurs.
Toutefois, si vous voulez vérifier que vous avez fait le bon choix, je vous conseille de jeter un coup d’œil aux résultats obtenus par Long Zheng dans sa comparaison la plus juste et définitive des navigateurs.</description></item><item><title>Best browser out there</title><link>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 13:51:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there/</guid><description>So, if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this blog you have probably already downloaded and installed the latest version of Internet Explorer and/or Firefox and arbitrarily taken sides in the raging Browser Wars.
Well, if you need/want to verify that you&amp;rsquo;ve made the right choice take a look at the results of Long Zheng&amp;rsquo;s fairest and most definite browser comparison.
Comments: Colan Kotpersky - Nov 4, 2008
Whats up with best browser, browsers are becoming unimportant, its the content and the applications that counts in my opinion and neither Fox or IE or Other Browser people are thinking about this.</description></item><item><title>El mejor navegador disponible</title><link>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there-es/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 13:51:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/04/best-browser-out-there-es/</guid><description>Si está leyendo este blog probablemente ya ha bajado e instalado las últimas versiones de Internet Explorer y/o Firefox y tomado partido arbitrariamente en la Guerra de navegadores.
Bueno, si quiere/necesita verificar que ha escogido correctamente, le recomiendo ver los resultados obtenido por Long Zheng en su comparación justa y definitiva de navigadores.</description></item></channel></rss>