<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Korea on madd0's tech blog</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/tag/korea/</link><description>Recent content in Korea on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.madd0.com/tag/korea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Music in Seoul</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</guid><description>There was one thing I loved about Seoul and it&amp;rsquo;s that, wherever you were, if there was a little green near you, there was music to be heard. Gyongbokgung was not an exception. Indeed, I actually got to see the artists behind the music and one of them was glad to perform before the camera:</description></item><item><title>Shaken, not stirred</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 19:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in a plane heading to Seoul right now to participate in the finals of Imagine Cup 2007 and this will be the first of, hopefully, many posts covering the event. A couple of remarks: since I am a contestant and not a journalist, I will not have a lot of time for writing, so for a while all posts will be only in English (the text will be available on all three feeds, though); and since Internet access will apparently be difficult to come by with, I will probably be posting by batches when I get the chance to go online.</description></item><item><title>The road to Seoul - powered by Virtual Earth</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/31/the-road-to-seoul-powered-by-virtual-earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/31/the-road-to-seoul-powered-by-virtual-earth/</guid><description>An interesting idea by the Imagine Cup team: map the locations of all teams on their way to Seoul this weekend for the Imagine Cup finals.
It would have been even better if they had asked us to actually locate ourselves on the map, because I&amp;rsquo;m sure nowhere near the south of France right now.
So, idea for next time: a mash-up using plazes and Virtual Earth, now that would have been cool&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>