<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Air Tweets</title><link>/2009/10/30/air-tweets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/30/air-tweets/</guid><description>It has been suggested that I’m addicted to Twitter. This is, of course, nonsense, as evidenced by my stats ;)
If I were addicted to Twitter, however, Lufthansa’s MySkyStatus is the Twitter/Facebook app I’d be really looking forward to use. Actually, who am I kidding? The only reason I haven’t actually used it is because I have no plans to get on a plane anytime soon.
So, what’s it all about?</description></item><item><title>Tweets aéreos</title><link>/2009/10/30/air-tweets-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/30/air-tweets-es/</guid><description>Se ha dicho que soy adicto a Twitter. Esto es, por supuesto, absurdo, como lo demuestran mis estadísticas ;)
Sin embargo, si de verdad fuera adicto a Twitter, MySkyStatus de Lufthansa es la aplicación de Twitter/Facebook que me moriría por utilizar. ¿La verdad, a quién estoy engañando? La única razón por la que no he usado el servicio, es porque no tengo planes en este momento de tomar el avión.</description></item><item><title>Tweets aériens</title><link>/2009/10/30/air-tweets-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/30/air-tweets-fr/</guid><description>J’ai entendu des gens suggérer que suis accro à Twitter. Ceci est, bien entendu, absurde, comme en témoignent mes stats ;)
Si j’étais dépendant de Twitter, cependant, MySkyStatus de Lufthansa est l’application Twitter/Facebook que j’aurais vraiment hâte d’utiliser. En fait, je ne suis même pas crédible : la seule raison pour laquelle que je ne l’ai pas encore utilisé, c’est parce que je n’ai pas du tout prévu de prendre l’avion dans le court terme.</description></item><item><title>Où suis-je ? Où vais-je ?</title><link>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</guid><description>Des questions que je me pose bien plus souvent que je ne le devrais, mais non, ce n’est pas de mes problèmes de mémoire que je voulais parler. La question que l’on m’a posée c’est : où suis-je “virtuellement” ? Je tweete à peine, je ne blogue plus, ni ici ni là …
L’explication est simple ; et double ou triple à la fois. D’une part, si je ne dis rien, c’est probablement parce que je n’ai rien à dire, mais vous savez aussi que souvent quand je n’ai rien à dire je finis par dire quelque chose quand même, donc que se passe-t-il ?</description></item><item><title>Shaken, not stirred</title><link>/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 19:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in a plane heading to Seoul right now to participate in the finals of Imagine Cup 2007 and this will be the first of, hopefully, many posts covering the event. A couple of remarks: since I am a contestant and not a journalist, I will not have a lot of time for writing, so for a while all posts will be only in English (the text will be available on all three feeds, though); and since Internet access will apparently be difficult to come by with, I will probably be posting by batches when I get the chance to go online.</description></item><item><title>Crossing oceans... (part II, the return)</title><link>/2007/02/28/crossing-oceans-part-ii-the-return/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 16:34:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/02/28/crossing-oceans-part-ii-the-return/</guid><description>So, here I am, preparing to go back to Paris. And, by preparing, I mean I’m already at the airport in San José where they do offer free WiFi (unlike Barajas).
There was lots of work to do last week: a full schedule of meetings last Monday and Tuesday and after that, a less-full schedule of family to meet until today, as well as a passport to make. I’ll be talking about the passport later this week (or in a couple of weeks, we’ll see) in order to put the “tech” back in my blog.</description></item><item><title>Crossing oceans… (part I)</title><link>/2007/02/28/crossing-oceans-part-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 01:33:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/02/28/crossing-oceans-part-i/</guid><description>Oops, I forgot to post this when arriving at Costa Rica. I&amp;rsquo;ll post now, and you can read everything about me leaving in the next entry ;)
I am sitting on the floor in Barajas airport in Madrid right now. It&amp;rsquo;s 09:24 local time and the airport is as empty as they get. This entry will not be posted right away though. I have no intention (or the means) to pay 5€ for 30 minutes of wireless Internet access (I’ll talk about this again later.</description></item></channel></rss>