<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Channel 8 on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/channel-8/</link><description>Recent content in Channel 8 on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/channel-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Next stop: Korea</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea/</guid><description>I left some IE7 tabs open before I took the plane to Costa Rica and, while closing them today, I stumbled upon Channel 8 again, where a new video is already online. This video, that presents Bill Gates and Craig Mundie talking about Imagine Cup, reminded me that I forgot to make a very important announcement because it happened right when my blog died:
I qualified for the Imagine Cup finals in Korea!</description></item><item><title>Próxima parada: Corea</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-es/</guid><description>Dejé algunos tabs de IE7 abiertos antes de coger el avión para Costa Rica y, mientras los cerraba hoy, volví a caer en la página de Channel 8, en la que ya se puede ver un nuevo video. Este video, en el cual Bill Gates y Craig Mundie hablan de Imagine Cup, me recordó que se me había olvidado hacer un anuncio muy importante ya que sucedió justo cuando mi blog se murió:</description></item><item><title>Prochain arrêt : la Corée</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-fr/</guid><description>J&amp;rsquo;ai laissé quelques onglets IE7 ouverts avant de prendre l&amp;rsquo;avion pour le Costa Rica et, en les fermant aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, je suis encore tombé sur Channel 8, où l&amp;rsquo;on peut déjà voir une nouvelle vidéo. Cette vidéo, dans laquelle Bill Gates et Craig Mundie parlent d&amp;rsquo;Imagine Cup, m&amp;rsquo;a rappelé que j&amp;rsquo;avais oublié de faire une annonce très importante parce que c&amp;rsquo;est arrivé juste quand mon blog est mort :
Je suis qualifié pour la finale d&amp;rsquo;Imagine Cup en Corée !</description></item><item><title>Nothing on TV? Switch to Channel 8!</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know when this went online because I&amp;rsquo;ve been mostly disconnected lately, with the moving and all, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep up with the blogosphere, but still I would like to present you a new Microsoft site.
First, do you know about Channel 9 and Channel 10?
Channel 9 was one of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s first initiatives to open up to the general public. Today it&amp;rsquo;s a website where developers, IT pros and other geeks can learn everything about past, present and future Microsoft technologies via videos, forums, blogs, etc.</description></item><item><title>¿Nada en la tele? ¡Ponga Channel 8!</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-es/</guid><description>No sé hace cuánto se lanzó porque he estado bastante desconectado últimamente, con la mudanza y todo, así que no he podido seguir de cerca la blogosfera, pero igual quisiera presentarles un nuevo sitio de Microsoft.
Pero primero, ¿ya conocen Channel 9 y Channel 10?
Channel 9 fue una de las primeras iniciativas de Microsoft para abrirse más hacia el público general. Hoy es un sitio donde desarrolladores, IT pros y otros geeks pueden aprender todo sobre las tecnologías Microsoft pasadas, presentes y futuras vía vídeos, foros, blogs, etc.</description></item><item><title>Rien à la télé ? Zappez sur Channel 8 !</title><link>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 18:38:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/23/nothing-on-tv-switch-to-channel-8-fr/</guid><description>Je ne sais pas vraiment quand ça a été lancé parce que j&amp;rsquo;ai été assez déconnecté ces derniers temps, avec le déménagement et tout, du coup je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas trop suivi la blogosphère, mais je voudrais quand même vous présenter un nouveau site Microsoft.
Tout d&amp;rsquo;abord, connaissez-vous Channel 9 et Channel 10 ?
Channel 9 a été l&amp;rsquo;une des premières initiatives de Microsoft pour s&amp;rsquo;ouvrir au grand public. Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui c&amp;rsquo;est un site où les développeurs, IT pros et autres geeks peuvent tout apprendre à propos des technologies Microsoft passées, présentes et futures à travers des vidéos, forums, blogs, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>