<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DIY on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/diy/</link><description>Recent content in DIY on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Máquina de escribir a punto de hacerse USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-es/</guid><description>Hace un rato compré una máquina de escribir (la de la foto) con única intención de, algún día, conectarla a mi computadora con un cable USB. Por supuesto, yo sé que una máquina de escribir sería un teclado muy ruidoso, pero a quién le importa? :P
También sé que, obviamente, otros lo han hecho antes, pero una vez más, a quién le importa?
El primer paso fue comprar la máquina de escribir.</description></item><item><title>Machine à écrire sur le point de devenir USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb-fr/</guid><description>Il y a un moment j&amp;rsquo;ai acheté une machine à écrire (celle de la photo) avec l&amp;rsquo;intention d&amp;rsquo;un jour pouvoir la brancher sur mon ordinateur en USB. Oui, je sais, une machine à écrire fait un clavier très bruyant, mais on s&amp;rsquo;en fout, non? :P
Je ne suis évidemment pas la première personne à le faire, mais encore une fois, on s&amp;rsquo;en fout, non?
Alors, la première étape était d&amp;rsquo;acheter la machine à écrire.</description></item><item><title>Typewriter soon to be USB</title><link>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 17:11:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/14/typewriter-soon-to-be-usb/</guid><description>A while ago I bought a typewriter (the one in the picture) with the intention of one day being able to connect it to the computer using a USB cable. Sure, a typewriter will make for a noisy keyboard, but who cares? :P
I&amp;rsquo;m obviously not the first one to do it, but again, who cares?
So, the first step was buying the typewriter. Thanks to eBay that&amp;rsquo;s done. And, if you look carefully, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the keyboard&amp;rsquo;s layout is almost like my Swiss French layout that I like so much.</description></item></channel></rss>