<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Experience on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/user-experience/</link><description>Recent content in User Experience on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/user-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Qu’y a-t-il dans un nom ?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-fr/</guid><description>Qu’y a-t-il dans un nom ? Ce que nous appelons une rose embaumerait autant sous un autre nom.
— Roméo et Juliette (II, ii, 1-2)
Ce matin j’ai appris par Engadget que ce qui était connu jusqu’aujourd’hui sous le nom Project Natal devient Kinect for Xbox 360, comme cela a été annoncé juste avant l’E3 par ni plus ni moins qu’une troupe de 76 membres du Cirque du Soleil. J’ai eu deux réactions :</description></item><item><title>What’s in a name?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? That which we call a rose By any other name would smell as sweet.
— Romeo and Juliet (II, ii, 1-2)
This morning I learnt through Engadget that what was known until now as Project Natal is now called Kinect for Xbox 360, as revealed just before E3 by none other than a 76-person cast of Cirque du Soleil. I had two reactions:
Why wasn’t I invited?</description></item><item><title>¿Por qué no tomas otro nombre?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-es/</guid><description>¿Por qué no tomas otro nombre? La rosa no dejaría de ser rosa, y de esparcir su aroma, aunque se llamase de otro modo.
— Romeo y Julieta (II, ii, 1-2)
Esta mañana leí en Engadget que lo que se conocía hasta hoy como Project Natal se llama ahora Kinect for Xbox 360, como lo reveló justo antes del E3 un grupo de 76 artistas del Cirque du Soleil. Yo reaccioné de dos formas:</description></item><item><title>Your Avatars on the New Xbox Experience</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience/</guid><description>I was really looking forward to it because I wasn’t fan of the “blades” at all, so I obviously logged on to Xbox LIVE last Wednesday to download the New Xbox Experience (NXE).
One of the new features of the NXE is the creation of avatars, which I was kind of forced to test even though I really, really needed to sleep. Avatars are not something new; we already had Miis on the Wii for example.</description></item><item><title>Sus avatares de la Nueva Experiencia Xbox</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-es/</guid><description>Como no me gustaba para nada la interfaz “blades”, el miércoles pasado me conecté a Xbox LIVE para bajar la Nueva Experiencia Xbox o NXE (siglas de New Xbox Experience).
Una de las nuevas funcionalidades de la NXE es la creación de avatares, lo que me vi más o menos obligado a probar aunque de veras necesitaba dormir. Los avatares no son algo nuevo; ya teníamos Miis en la Wii por ejemplo.</description></item><item><title>Vos avatars sur la Nouvelle Expérience Xbox</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-fr/</guid><description>Pas fan du dashboard “blades” c’est avec impatience que je me suis connecté sur Xbox LIVE mercredi dernier pour télécharger la “Nouvelle Expérience Xbox” ou NXE (pour New Xbox Experience).
Une des nouvelles fonctionnalités de la NXE est la création d&amp;rsquo;avatars, que je me suis vu plus ou moins obligé de tester, même si j’avais vraiment, vraiment besoin de dormir. Les avatars ne sont pas quelque chose de nouveau ; nous avions déjà les Miis sur la Wii par exemple.</description></item><item><title>New Xbox 360 Dashboard coming Nov. 19</title><link>/2008/10/09/new-xbox-360-dashboard-coming-nov-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 07:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/09/new-xbox-360-dashboard-coming-nov-19/</guid><description>We’ve been waiting for it impatiently—or at least I have. It was initially rumored for October, but Microsoft officially announced yesterday at TGS 2008 that the new Xbox 360 Dashboard will be rolling out on November 19.
It will be available in 26 countries and localized in 19 languages. As you can see from the screenshot above (and more in this Joystiq gallery), not only are we getting a completely different user interface, but the experience will change too as this new version focuses strongly on bringing you and your friends closer to the Xbox by introducing avatars and allowing more interaction among friends.</description></item></channel></rss>