<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 07:23:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>En vrac mercredi 18 janvier 2012</title><link>/2012/01/18/en-vrac-mercredi-18-janvier-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 07:23:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/01/18/en-vrac-mercredi-18-janvier-2012/</guid><description>Rodrigo y Gabriela C.U.B.A. J&amp;rsquo;ai reçu un mail hier de Rodrigo et Gabriela. Non, il ne s&amp;rsquo;agit pas des cousins de l&amp;rsquo;autre côté de l&amp;rsquo;île, il s&amp;rsquo;agit de deux mexicains qui habitent en Irlande ; plus important, c&amp;rsquo;est un duo de guitaristes exceptionnel ! Vous les avez peut-être entendu à Solidays en 2010 ou, plus récemment, dans la BO du dernier Pirates des Caraïbes.
Mais, pour quoi j&amp;rsquo;en parle ici ?</description></item><item><title>Jake Shimabukuro et son ukulele à TEDx Tokyo</title><link>/2010/05/18/jake-shimabukuro-et-son-ukulele-agrave-tedx-tokyo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 09:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/18/jake-shimabukuro-et-son-ukulele-agrave-tedx-tokyo/</guid><description>J&amp;rsquo;avais déjà entendu Jake Shimabukuro quelque part, mais je n&amp;rsquo;arrive pas à me souvenir où. Je savais qu&amp;rsquo;il était bon, mais cette vidéo enregistrée à TEDx Tokyo m&amp;rsquo;a laissée bouche bée pendant 22 minutes.
Prenez le temps de regarder la vidéo en entier, ça vaut vraiment la peine :
Il joue 3 morceaux :
Un &amp;ldquo;Flamenco ukulele&amp;rdquo; que, je pense, est une composition originale &amp;ldquo;Ave Maria&amp;rdquo; de Schubert, à l&amp;rsquo;ukulele !</description></item><item><title>History of the Internet</title><link>/2009/01/09/history-of-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 06:09:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/01/09/history-of-the-internet/</guid><description>Very nice video created by Melih Bilgil as part of his diploma project PICOL illustrating the history of the Internet from 1957 to 1990.
He uses the icons of his design to represent every element of the story. That and a well written voice over, make for a very interesting, easy to understand video. I’m actually considering asking my teachers to play this as an introduction to our web development classes.</description></item><item><title>Music in Seoul</title><link>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</guid><description>There was one thing I loved about Seoul and it&amp;rsquo;s that, wherever you were, if there was a little green near you, there was music to be heard. Gyongbokgung was not an exception. Indeed, I actually got to see the artists behind the music and one of them was glad to perform before the camera:</description></item></channel></rss>