<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Facebook on madd0's tech blog</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/tag/facebook/</link><description>Recent content in Facebook on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.madd0.com/tag/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Air Tweets</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets/</guid><description>It has been suggested that I’m addicted to Twitter. This is, of course, nonsense, as evidenced by my stats ;)
If I were addicted to Twitter, however, Lufthansa’s MySkyStatus is the Twitter/Facebook app I’d be really looking forward to use. Actually, who am I kidding? The only reason I haven’t actually used it is because I have no plans to get on a plane anytime soon.
So, what’s it all about?</description></item><item><title>Tweets aéreos</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets-es/</guid><description>Se ha dicho que soy adicto a Twitter. Esto es, por supuesto, absurdo, como lo demuestran mis estadísticas ;)
Sin embargo, si de verdad fuera adicto a Twitter, MySkyStatus de Lufthansa es la aplicación de Twitter/Facebook que me moriría por utilizar. ¿La verdad, a quién estoy engañando? La única razón por la que no he usado el servicio, es porque no tengo planes en este momento de tomar el avión.</description></item><item><title>Tweets aériens</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 05:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2009/10/30/air-tweets-fr/</guid><description>J’ai entendu des gens suggérer que suis accro à Twitter. Ceci est, bien entendu, absurde, comme en témoignent mes stats ;)
Si j’étais dépendant de Twitter, cependant, MySkyStatus de Lufthansa est l’application Twitter/Facebook que j’aurais vraiment hâte d’utiliser. En fait, je ne suis même pas crédible : la seule raison pour laquelle que je ne l’ai pas encore utilisé, c’est parce que je n’ai pas du tout prévu de prendre l’avion dans le court terme.</description></item></channel></rss>