<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Videos on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/videos/</link><description>Recent content in Videos on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 13:50:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lèche-vitrine augmenté avec Kinect</title><link>/2012/07/26/leche-vitrine-augmente-avec-kinect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 13:50:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/07/26/leche-vitrine-augmente-avec-kinect/</guid><description>Je vous invite à regarder la vidéo du projet Sightlines qui utilise les fonctionnalités de head tracking de Kinect pour Windows afin de superposer des information sur un objet qui se trouve derrière un écran LCD transparent.
Une technologie qui pourrait être utilisée dans les vitrines des magasins ou les musées dans avenir proche ? Je m&amp;rsquo;en fous un peu des vitrines des magasins, mais dans les musées ça pourrait être extrêmement intéressant et le potentiel pédagogique est énorme !</description></item><item><title>Les enfants et la vie privée à TEDx</title><link>/2011/04/04/les-enfants-et-la-vie-priveacutee-agrave-tedx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 07:38:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/04/04/les-enfants-et-la-vie-priveacutee-agrave-tedx/</guid><description>J’étais sur le point de faire un “Mark all as read” sur les billets restants dans la catégorie “High noise” de mes flux RSS, quand j’ai remarqué la vidéo de Cory Doctrow à TEDx Observer. Elle a attiré mon attention parce qu’elle parle essentiellement de la même chose que mon avant-dernier billet : les enfants et Internet.
Je n’ai pas d’enfants et je ne compte pas en avoir—pas dans le court ou le moyen terme en tout cas—mais c’est bien vos enfants qui, plus tard, vont payer ma retraite (enfin, longue discussion pour une autre fois, mais admettons) donc c’est dans mon meilleur intérêt qu’ils soient sains de corps et d’esprit pour arriver à l’âge adulte.</description></item><item><title>Valse Irritation d'après Nokia et la découverte de The EG</title><link>/2010/01/13/valse-irritation-dapregraves-nokia-et-la-deacutecouverte-de-the-eg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 05:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/13/valse-irritation-dapregraves-nokia-et-la-deacutecouverte-de-the-eg/</guid><description>Je découvre ce matin cette composition pour piano, qui date apparemment de quelques années, écrire à partir de la traditionnelle sonnerie Nokia par le pianiste québécois Marc-André Hamelin.
Plus intéressant peut-être que ce morceau, je découvre la conférence The EG—The Entertainment Gathering. Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une conférence à la TED. D&amp;rsquo;ailleurs, certaines des conférences sont carrément disponibles sur le site TED. Cette conférence est cependant plus orientée divertissement ou loisir, son but étant de redéfinir la manière dont on entretient nos idées (de l&amp;rsquo;anglais entertain ideas).</description></item><item><title>Interview avec Eric Mittelette aux TechDays 09</title><link>/2009/04/20/interview-avec-eric-mittelette-aux-techdays-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 04:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/04/20/interview-avec-eric-mittelette-aux-techdays-09/</guid><description>En février, lors de Microsoft TechDays à Paris, je n’ai pas assisté à une seule conférence (ce n’est pas grave, il y a toujours les webcasts) mais j’ai quand même pu arpenter le salon pendant trois jours pour rencontrer du monde entre autres pour la WebTV de SUPINFO.
J’ai fait, avec d’autres, plein d’interviews pour aborder à peu près tous les sujets : les communications unifiées, les femmes dans l’IT, les communautés, etc.</description></item><item><title>What do you know about IT?</title><link>/2009/03/20/what-do-you-know-about-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 13:55:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/20/what-do-you-know-about-it/</guid><description>Pierre sent me a DM to let me know that I appear for a second or so in this Microsoft video:
I’m guessing that many of you won’t watch it until the end, so I’m just going to copy the part that caught my attention the most:
I bet you didn’t know this
42% of global IT employment…
relies on Microsoft technologies.
Wow!
Finally, as a side note to myself: do not accept interviews late at night, especially if you hadn’t slept much the nights before ;)</description></item><item><title>If my kids turn out like this…</title><link>/2009/03/10/if-my-kids-turn-out-like-thishellip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 10:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/10/if-my-kids-turn-out-like-thishellip/</guid><description>[youtube As funny and cute as this little girl talking about Visual Studio 2008 might be, I’d be really, really scared if my kids turned out like this :P (that is, assuming anyone would actually dare have kids with me in the first place).
Oh, and did she actually test the WPF designer and XAML Intellisense? All the rest, I pretty much agree, but I’m really looking forward to better WPF and XAML support in VS 2010 ;)</description></item><item><title>History of the Internet</title><link>/2009/01/09/history-of-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 06:09:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/01/09/history-of-the-internet/</guid><description>Very nice video created by Melih Bilgil as part of his diploma project PICOL illustrating the history of the Internet from 1957 to 1990.
He uses the icons of his design to represent every element of the story. That and a well written voice over, make for a very interesting, easy to understand video. I’m actually considering asking my teachers to play this as an introduction to our web development classes.</description></item><item><title>Great people meet at La Sorbonne</title><link>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I posted the pictures of the Imagine Cup conference that took place in Paris and during which I had the opportunity to interview Bill Gates.
An event like that was of course filmed and now the videos are also available for online viewing and for download from the web site of Microsoft France.
There are six videos:
French (well, French and Costa Rican :P) finalists from 2007 (French) Bernard Charlès, CEO Dassault Systèmes (French) Ora Ito, Designer (French) Andrew Herbert, Microsoft Research Cambridge (English) Bill Gates, Microsoft Chairman (English) Q&amp;amp;A with Bill Gates (you can see me here again) (English) Click on &amp;ldquo;Voir &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to view the video online or &amp;ldquo;Télécharger&amp;rdquo; to download.</description></item><item><title>Bionic monkey-talk at TED</title><link>/2007/12/30/bionic-monkeytalk-at-ted/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/30/bionic-monkeytalk-at-ted/</guid><description>OK, maybe the title doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything better. So how about you just watch the videos?
I was barely finished with last week&amp;rsquo;s TED post when I stumbled upon the first of this week&amp;rsquo;s recommendations. I know I said that TED videos were only 18 minutes long, but I guess when you&amp;rsquo;re Jane Goodall you&amp;rsquo;re inherently expected to need a little more:
As inspiring as Mrs.</description></item><item><title>The Devil Wears Prada to the next Live Meeting</title><link>/2007/12/25/the-devil-wears-prada-to-the-next-live-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 20:36:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/25/the-devil-wears-prada-to-the-next-live-meeting/</guid><description>For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the same routing on Christmas day:
Wake up, unwrap presents, have breakfast, watch a movie, visit relatives.
Of course, over time, things have changed slightly. Most notably, the time I wake up, that fact most presents are actually opened the night before, breakfast became brunch and most of my relatives now live a 14-hour flight away.
Movie time didn&amp;rsquo;t change, though, and today&amp;rsquo;s was The Devil Wears Prada.</description></item><item><title>Recherchez à la manière Firefox sous Internet Explorer</title><link>/2006/10/21/recherchez-agrave-la-maniegravere-firefox-sous-internet-explorer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2006 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/10/21/recherchez-agrave-la-maniegravere-firefox-sous-internet-explorer/</guid><description>Que vous utilisiez Internet Explorer en tant que navigateur principal ou simplement comme un dernier recours, si vous avez déjà utilisé Firefox, sa fonctionnalité de recherche vous manque probablement lorsque vous “travaillez” sous IE.
Plus maintenant ! La IE team a publié sur leur blog une liste de Must Have Add-Ons for IE7 (add-ons indispensables pour IE7, mais ils marchent aussi avec les versions précédentes ) et parmi eux se trouve Inline Search, un add-on qui remplace Ctrl+F (mais pas Edit &amp;gt; Find on this Page) avec une barre à outils avec la même fonctionnalité de Firefox.</description></item></channel></rss>