<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Me on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/me/</link><description>Recent content in Me on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Où suis-je ? Où vais-je ?</title><link>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</guid><description>Des questions que je me pose bien plus souvent que je ne le devrais, mais non, ce n’est pas de mes problèmes de mémoire que je voulais parler. La question que l’on m’a posée c’est : où suis-je “virtuellement” ? Je tweete à peine, je ne blogue plus, ni ici ni là …
L’explication est simple ; et double ou triple à la fois. D’une part, si je ne dis rien, c’est probablement parce que je n’ai rien à dire, mais vous savez aussi que souvent quand je n’ai rien à dire je finis par dire quelque chose quand même, donc que se passe-t-il ?</description></item><item><title>What do you know about IT?</title><link>/2009/03/20/what-do-you-know-about-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 13:55:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/20/what-do-you-know-about-it/</guid><description>Pierre sent me a DM to let me know that I appear for a second or so in this Microsoft video:
I’m guessing that many of you won’t watch it until the end, so I’m just going to copy the part that caught my attention the most:
I bet you didn’t know this
42% of global IT employment…
relies on Microsoft technologies.
Wow!
Finally, as a side note to myself: do not accept interviews late at night, especially if you hadn’t slept much the nights before ;)</description></item><item><title>Je serais presque célèbre !</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-fr/</guid><description>Il y a quelques semaines, j&amp;rsquo;ai été suivi par un caméraman pendant une journée pour un reportage pour France 24. Je savais que ça allait passer à la télé, sur leur site web et sur YouTube pendant l&amp;rsquo;été et ils m&amp;rsquo;ont dit qu&amp;rsquo;ils me tiendraient informé. Mais ce n&amp;rsquo;est pas comme ça que les choses se passent de nos jours&amp;hellip;
Dimanche dernier, un dimanche matin comme les autres, je me lève à 13h et j&amp;rsquo;ouvre mon PC.</description></item><item><title>¡Ya soy casi famoso!</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-es/</guid><description>Hace unas semanas me siguió durante todo un día un camarógrafo para hacer un reportaje para France 24 (un canal de televisión francés). Yo sabía que iba a pasar en la televisión, su página web y en YouTube en algún momento este verano y me dijeron que me mantendrían al tanto. Pero así no es como funcionan las cosas hoy en día&amp;hellip;
El domingo pasado, una mañana dominical como las otras, a eso de la 1 p.</description></item><item><title>I'm almost famous!</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I was followed around by a cameraman for a piece for France 24 (a French TV station). I knew that it would be broadcast on TV, their web site and on YouTube sometime during the summer and they told me that they&amp;rsquo;d let me know. But that&amp;rsquo;s not how things work nowadays&amp;hellip;
Last Sunday, a regular Sunday morning, I woke up at around 1 p.m. and opened my computer.</description></item><item><title>Great people meet at La Sorbonne</title><link>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I posted the pictures of the Imagine Cup conference that took place in Paris and during which I had the opportunity to interview Bill Gates.
An event like that was of course filmed and now the videos are also available for online viewing and for download from the web site of Microsoft France.
There are six videos:
French (well, French and Costa Rican :P) finalists from 2007 (French) Bernard Charlès, CEO Dassault Systèmes (French) Ora Ito, Designer (French) Andrew Herbert, Microsoft Research Cambridge (English) Bill Gates, Microsoft Chairman (English) Q&amp;amp;A with Bill Gates (you can see me here again) (English) Click on &amp;ldquo;Voir &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to view the video online or &amp;ldquo;Télécharger&amp;rdquo; to download.</description></item><item><title>Photos with BillG</title><link>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 12:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</guid><description>As usual these days, there were all sorts of cameras present at yesterday&amp;rsquo;s activity. This is great because I of course couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my own pictures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a selection of pictures that I have received:
Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s me, to his left first and then to his right.
And here are links I&amp;rsquo;ve received/found with pictures of the event. I&amp;rsquo;ll be editing these as I find/get new ones:
G-IT Photos by Séverin Ferrand Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Emmanuel de Taillac Photos by Maxime Gaillard Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Johanna Piou</description></item></channel></rss>