<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>London on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/london/</link><description>Recent content in London on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does this thing have a manual?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual/</guid><description>Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think an escalator needed one, but the numbers seem to say different:
For those who can&amp;rsquo;t read the poor quality text, it says &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;.
The number drew my attention for two reasons:
What are the probabilities of the number of injuries on escalators being a power of 2? How can there be almost 3 injuries per day on something as trivial as an escalator? (that&amp;rsquo;s an interrobang, in case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering) Sure, the escalators on the London tube can be impressive:</description></item><item><title>Y a un manuel utilisateur pour ce machin ?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-fr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-fr/</guid><description>Je ne pensais pas qu&amp;rsquo;un escalator en aurait besoin, mais les chiffres semblent indiquer le contraire :
Pour ceux qui n&amp;rsquo;arrivent pas à lire le texte, c&amp;rsquo;est marqué &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;, c&amp;rsquo;est-à-dire &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;an dernier : 1024 blessés&amp;rdquo;.
Le chiffre a attiré mon attention pour deux raisons :
Quelles sont les probabilités que le nombre de blessés dans un escalator soit une puissance de 2 ? Comment peut-il y avoir presque 3 blessés par jour dans quelque chose d&amp;rsquo;aussi trivial qu&amp;rsquo;un escalator ?</description></item><item><title>¿Hay un manual para esta cosa?</title><link>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-es/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/05/does-this-thing-have-a-manual-es/</guid><description>Pues, nunca pensé que una escalera eléctrica necesitara uno, pero las cifras indican lo contrario:
Para los que no logran leer el texto, dice &amp;ldquo;Last year: 1,024 injuries&amp;rdquo;, o sea &amp;ldquo;El año pasado: 1024 heridos&amp;rdquo;.
El número me llamó la atención por dos razones:
¿Cuáles son las probabilidades de que el número de heridos en escaleras eléctricas sea una potencia de 2? ¿Cómo puede haber casi 3 heridos por día en algo tan trivial como una escalera eléctrica?</description></item></channel></rss>