<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio on madd0's tech blog</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/tag/visual-studio/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 02:26:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.madd0.com/tag/visual-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visual Studio 2008: ¿Qué pasó con Intellisense?</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go-es/</guid><description>Por supuesto que Intellisense todavía existe en Visual Studio 2008. Si algo ha cambiado, es tal vez un cierto número de mejoras.
Por ejemplo, ya me ha pasado miles de veces y apuesto a que a ustedes también: estoy escribiendo código, la ventana de Intellisense aparece. Aprecio que la ventana esté ahí porque generalmente me ayuda a programar más rápido, pero en este preciso momento me gustaría ver el código que está debajo.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008: Where did Intellisense go?</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 02:26:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go/</guid><description>Of course Intellisense is still there in Visual Studio 2008. If anything, it&amp;rsquo;s undergone several nice improvements.
For example, it has happened to me thousands of times and I bet it has happened to you too: you are writing code, the Intellisense window pops up. You appreciate that it&amp;rsquo;s there because you like how it helps you write code faster, but at that precise moment you&amp;rsquo;d really wish it would get out of the way so you could see the code that&amp;rsquo;s underneath.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008: Où est passé l'Intellisense ?</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 02:26:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2007/07/30/visual-studio-2008-where-did-intellisense-go-fr/</guid><description>Bien sûr qu&amp;rsquo;Intellisense existe toujours sous Visual Studio 2008. S&amp;rsquo;il y a quelque chose qui a changé, c&amp;rsquo;est peut être un certain nombre d&amp;rsquo;améliorations.
Par exemple, ça m&amp;rsquo;est arrivé plein de fois et je parie qu&amp;rsquo;à vous aussi : vous écrivez du code, la fenêtre Intellisense apparaît. Vous en êtes reconnaissant parce qu&amp;rsquo;elle vous permet en général de coder plus vite, mais à cet instant précis vous aimeriez qu&amp;rsquo;elle disparaisse pour voir ce qu&amp;rsquo;il y a derrière.</description></item></channel></rss>