<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Typography on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/typography/</link><description>Recent content in Typography on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/typography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog/</guid><description>This famous phrase has been used for a long time by typesetters, typographers and other professionals that need to use all 26 letters of the English alphabet. Today, courtesy of YouTube, I give you the illustrated version:
[Via Rocketboom]</description></item><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-es/</guid><description>Esta famose frase (en inglés por lo menos) ha sido utilisada desde hace mucho tiempo por tipógrafos, grafistas y otros profesionales que necesitan utilizar las 26 letras del alfabeto inglés. Hoy, gracias a YouTube, les propongo la versión ilustrada en video:
_LVo_aTo
[Via Rocketboom]
Comments: map quest.com charleston sc - Aug 1, 2014
The convenience of these machines is hard to match. People who love to cook prefer to have gadgets that will make your life easier in the kitchen.</description></item><item><title>The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.</title><link>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 08:15:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/31/the-quick-brown-fox-jumps-over-the-lazy-dog-fr/</guid><description>Cette phrase mythique (en anglais en tout cas) est utilisée depuis longtemps par des typographes, des graphistes et d’autres professionnels qui ont besoin d’utiliser toutes les 26 lettres de l’alphabet anglais. Aujourd’hui, grâce à YouTube, je vous propose la version illustrée en vidéo :
[Via Rocketboom]</description></item></channel></rss>