<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Imagine Cup on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/imagine-cup/</link><description>Recent content in Imagine Cup on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/imagine-cup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Où suis-je ? Où vais-je ?</title><link>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</guid><description>Des questions que je me pose bien plus souvent que je ne le devrais, mais non, ce n’est pas de mes problèmes de mémoire que je voulais parler. La question que l’on m’a posée c’est : où suis-je “virtuellement” ? Je tweete à peine, je ne blogue plus, ni ici ni là …
L’explication est simple ; et double ou triple à la fois. D’une part, si je ne dis rien, c’est probablement parce que je n’ai rien à dire, mais vous savez aussi que souvent quand je n’ai rien à dire je finis par dire quelque chose quand même, donc que se passe-t-il ?</description></item><item><title>SUPINFO représentée à la Finale Mondiale Imagine Cup</title><link>/2008/05/16/supinfo-repreacutesenteacutee-agrave-la-finale-mondiale-imagine-cup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 10:50:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/16/supinfo-repreacutesenteacutee-agrave-la-finale-mondiale-imagine-cup/</guid><description>Hier soir s’est déroulée la finale française de la catégorie Software Design de l’Imagine Cup de Microsoft. Sept finalistes, dont deux équipes SUPINFO, se disputaient la première place qui leur permettrait de représenter les couleurs de leur école et de leur pays à la finale internationale qui se déroulera du 3 au 8 juillet 2008 à Paris.
C’est en présence notamment d’Eric Boustouller–Directeur Général de Microsoft France, de Jean-Louis Missika–Adjoint au Maire de Paris, chargé de l’innovation, de la recherche et des universités, et de Chantal Jouanno–Présidente de l’Agence de l’environnement et de la maîtrise de l’énergie, mais aussi de notre Président, Alick Mouriesse, que cette première place, tant convoitée, à été décernée à l’équipe Smart Cooking, constituée de Régis Hanol et Gauthier Chanliau–SUPINFO Montpellier, Sébastien Warin–SUPINFO Lille, et Jean-Noël Gauthier–Gobelins.</description></item><item><title>Great people meet at La Sorbonne</title><link>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I posted the pictures of the Imagine Cup conference that took place in Paris and during which I had the opportunity to interview Bill Gates.
An event like that was of course filmed and now the videos are also available for online viewing and for download from the web site of Microsoft France.
There are six videos:
French (well, French and Costa Rican :P) finalists from 2007 (French) Bernard Charlès, CEO Dassault Systèmes (French) Ora Ito, Designer (French) Andrew Herbert, Microsoft Research Cambridge (English) Bill Gates, Microsoft Chairman (English) Q&amp;amp;A with Bill Gates (you can see me here again) (English) Click on &amp;ldquo;Voir &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to view the video online or &amp;ldquo;Télécharger&amp;rdquo; to download.</description></item><item><title>Photos with BillG</title><link>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 12:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</guid><description>As usual these days, there were all sorts of cameras present at yesterday&amp;rsquo;s activity. This is great because I of course couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my own pictures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a selection of pictures that I have received:
Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s me, to his left first and then to his right.
And here are links I&amp;rsquo;ve received/found with pictures of the event. I&amp;rsquo;ll be editing these as I find/get new ones:
G-IT Photos by Séverin Ferrand Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Emmanuel de Taillac Photos by Maxime Gaillard Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Johanna Piou</description></item><item><title>Music in Seoul</title><link>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</guid><description>There was one thing I loved about Seoul and it&amp;rsquo;s that, wherever you were, if there was a little green near you, there was music to be heard. Gyongbokgung was not an exception. Indeed, I actually got to see the artists behind the music and one of them was glad to perform before the camera:</description></item><item><title>Imagine Cup 2007 Results, you cannot win every time</title><link>/2007/08/13/imagine-cup-2007-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 02:47:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/13/imagine-cup-2007-results/</guid><description>This post is long due, but I guess since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t concern me I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a hurry.
No, I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding. Of course, the most exciting moment of every competition is the announcement of the winners, so here they are, in case you are not interested in the official press release:
Software Design
First place: Thailand — Team 3KC Returns/Project LiveBook! Prachaya Phaisanwiphatpong, Vasan Chienmaneetaweesin, Jatupon Sukkasem, Pathompol Saeng-Uraiporn Second place: Korea — Team En#605/Project Finger Code Lim Chan-kyu, Min Kyoung-hoon, Lim Byoung-su, Jeong Ji-hyeon Third place: Jamaica — Team ICAD/Project CADI Imran Allie, Conroy Smith, Ayson Baxter, Damion Mitchell Embedded Development</description></item><item><title>Sleepless in Seoul</title><link>/2007/08/07/sleepless-in-seoul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 07:44:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/07/sleepless-in-seoul/</guid><description>Things moved so fast (or I was too slow) to write about the start of the 24-hour competition that took place from 14h GMT+9 on Monday 6th to 14h GMT+9 on Tuesday 7th.
The competition involved students from practically all categories, including mine: Interface Design.
Here are a couple of pictures I uploaded to Flick before starting:
The cubicles of all 6 Interface Design contestants.
This is our booth, before the competition started.</description></item><item><title>Shaken, not stirred</title><link>/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 19:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/04/shaken-not-stirred/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in a plane heading to Seoul right now to participate in the finals of Imagine Cup 2007 and this will be the first of, hopefully, many posts covering the event. A couple of remarks: since I am a contestant and not a journalist, I will not have a lot of time for writing, so for a while all posts will be only in English (the text will be available on all three feeds, though); and since Internet access will apparently be difficult to come by with, I will probably be posting by batches when I get the chance to go online.</description></item><item><title>The road to Seoul - powered by Virtual Earth</title><link>/2007/07/31/the-road-to-seoul-powered-by-virtual-earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/31/the-road-to-seoul-powered-by-virtual-earth/</guid><description>An interesting idea by the Imagine Cup team: map the locations of all teams on their way to Seoul this weekend for the Imagine Cup finals.
It would have been even better if they had asked us to actually locate ourselves on the map, because I&amp;rsquo;m sure nowhere near the south of France right now.
So, idea for next time: a mash-up using plazes and Virtual Earth, now that would have been cool&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Next stop: Korea</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea/</guid><description>I left some IE7 tabs open before I took the plane to Costa Rica and, while closing them today, I stumbled upon Channel 8 again, where a new video is already online. This video, that presents Bill Gates and Craig Mundie talking about Imagine Cup, reminded me that I forgot to make a very important announcement because it happened right when my blog died:
I qualified for the Imagine Cup finals in Korea!</description></item><item><title>Próxima parada: Corea</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-es/</guid><description>Dejé algunos tabs de IE7 abiertos antes de coger el avión para Costa Rica y, mientras los cerraba hoy, volví a caer en la página de Channel 8, en la que ya se puede ver un nuevo video. Este video, en el cual Bill Gates y Craig Mundie hablan de Imagine Cup, me recordó que se me había olvidado hacer un anuncio muy importante ya que sucedió justo cuando mi blog se murió:</description></item><item><title>Prochain arrêt : la Corée</title><link>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 12:53:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/25/next-stop-korea-fr/</guid><description>J&amp;rsquo;ai laissé quelques onglets IE7 ouverts avant de prendre l&amp;rsquo;avion pour le Costa Rica et, en les fermant aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, je suis encore tombé sur Channel 8, où l&amp;rsquo;on peut déjà voir une nouvelle vidéo. Cette vidéo, dans laquelle Bill Gates et Craig Mundie parlent d&amp;rsquo;Imagine Cup, m&amp;rsquo;a rappelé que j&amp;rsquo;avais oublié de faire une annonce très importante parce que c&amp;rsquo;est arrivé juste quand mon blog est mort :
Je suis qualifié pour la finale d&amp;rsquo;Imagine Cup en Corée !</description></item></channel></rss>