<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xbox 360 on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/xbox-360/</link><description>Recent content in Xbox 360 on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/xbox-360/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Qu’y a-t-il dans un nom ?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-fr/</guid><description>Qu’y a-t-il dans un nom ? Ce que nous appelons une rose embaumerait autant sous un autre nom.
— Roméo et Juliette (II, ii, 1-2)
Ce matin j’ai appris par Engadget que ce qui était connu jusqu’aujourd’hui sous le nom Project Natal devient Kinect for Xbox 360, comme cela a été annoncé juste avant l’E3 par ni plus ni moins qu’une troupe de 76 membres du Cirque du Soleil. J’ai eu deux réactions :</description></item><item><title>What’s in a name?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? That which we call a rose By any other name would smell as sweet.
— Romeo and Juliet (II, ii, 1-2)
This morning I learnt through Engadget that what was known until now as Project Natal is now called Kinect for Xbox 360, as revealed just before E3 by none other than a 76-person cast of Cirque du Soleil. I had two reactions:
Why wasn’t I invited?</description></item><item><title>¿Por qué no tomas otro nombre?</title><link>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 10:13:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/14/whatrsquos-in-a-name-es/</guid><description>¿Por qué no tomas otro nombre? La rosa no dejaría de ser rosa, y de esparcir su aroma, aunque se llamase de otro modo.
— Romeo y Julieta (II, ii, 1-2)
Esta mañana leí en Engadget que lo que se conocía hasta hoy como Project Natal se llama ahora Kinect for Xbox 360, como lo reveló justo antes del E3 un grupo de 76 artistas del Cirque du Soleil. Yo reaccioné de dos formas:</description></item><item><title>Your Avatars on the New Xbox Experience</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience/</guid><description>I was really looking forward to it because I wasn’t fan of the “blades” at all, so I obviously logged on to Xbox LIVE last Wednesday to download the New Xbox Experience (NXE).
One of the new features of the NXE is the creation of avatars, which I was kind of forced to test even though I really, really needed to sleep. Avatars are not something new; we already had Miis on the Wii for example.</description></item><item><title>Sus avatares de la Nueva Experiencia Xbox</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-es/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-es/</guid><description>Como no me gustaba para nada la interfaz “blades”, el miércoles pasado me conecté a Xbox LIVE para bajar la Nueva Experiencia Xbox o NXE (siglas de New Xbox Experience).
Una de las nuevas funcionalidades de la NXE es la creación de avatares, lo que me vi más o menos obligado a probar aunque de veras necesitaba dormir. Los avatares no son algo nuevo; ya teníamos Miis en la Wii por ejemplo.</description></item><item><title>Vos avatars sur la Nouvelle Expérience Xbox</title><link>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-fr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 21:30:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/26/your-avatars-on-the-new-xbox-experience-fr/</guid><description>Pas fan du dashboard “blades” c’est avec impatience que je me suis connecté sur Xbox LIVE mercredi dernier pour télécharger la “Nouvelle Expérience Xbox” ou NXE (pour New Xbox Experience).
Une des nouvelles fonctionnalités de la NXE est la création d&amp;rsquo;avatars, que je me suis vu plus ou moins obligé de tester, même si j’avais vraiment, vraiment besoin de dormir. Les avatars ne sont pas quelque chose de nouveau ; nous avions déjà les Miis sur la Wii par exemple.</description></item><item><title>New Xbox 360 Dashboard coming Nov. 19</title><link>/2008/10/09/new-xbox-360-dashboard-coming-nov-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 07:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/09/new-xbox-360-dashboard-coming-nov-19/</guid><description>We’ve been waiting for it impatiently—or at least I have. It was initially rumored for October, but Microsoft officially announced yesterday at TGS 2008 that the new Xbox 360 Dashboard will be rolling out on November 19.
It will be available in 26 countries and localized in 19 languages. As you can see from the screenshot above (and more in this Joystiq gallery), not only are we getting a completely different user interface, but the experience will change too as this new version focuses strongly on bringing you and your friends closer to the Xbox by introducing avatars and allowing more interaction among friends.</description></item><item><title>Xbox 360 Plays DivX and XviD!!!</title><link>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 21:24:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid/</guid><description>Finally! With today&amp;rsquo;s update, the Xbox 360 is now able to read DivX and XviD files (which you naturally acquired legally).
As soon as I heard about this, I of course turned on the beast and downloaded the necessary files (you need the new Xbox software and the codecs, which are downloaded separately).
It all works almost perfectly on my setup, which is a TVersity server streaming to the Dashboard on a PIII 500 MHz, 128 MB RAM.</description></item><item><title>¡¡¡El Xbox 360 lee los DivX y XviD!!!</title><link>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid-es/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 21:24:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid-es/</guid><description>¡Por fin! Después de la actualización de hoy, el Xbox 360 puede leer archivos DivX y XviD (que obviamente adquirieron legalmente).
A penas oí hablar de esto, encendí la bestia y bajé los archivos necesarios (se necesita el nuevo software Xbox y los codecs, que se bajan por separado).
Funciona casi perfectamente con mi configuración, que es un servidor TVersity que hace streaming hacia el Dashboard a partir de un PIII 500 MHz, 128 MB RAM.</description></item><item><title>La Xbox 360 lit les DivX et XviD !!!</title><link>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid-fr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 21:24:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/04/xbox-360-plays-divx-and-xvid-fr/</guid><description>Enfin ! Après la mise à jour d&amp;rsquo;aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, la Xbox 360 est maintenant capable de lire des fichiers DivX et XviD (que vous avez logiquement acquis légalement).
Dès que j&amp;rsquo;ai entendu parler de cette mise à jour, j&amp;rsquo;ai évidemment allumé la bête et téléchargé les fichiers nécessaires (vous aurez besoin du logiciel Xbox et des codecs, qui sont à télécharger séparément).
Le tout marche presque parfaitement sur ma configuration, qui est un serveur TVersity qui stream vers le Dashboard à partir d&amp;rsquo;un PIII 500 MHz, 128 Mo de RAM.</description></item><item><title>L'armée britannique utilise des manettes de Xbox 360 pour ses drones</title><link>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs-fr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:12:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs-fr/</guid><description>Je viens d&amp;rsquo;un pays qui n&amp;rsquo;a pas d&amp;rsquo;armée—d&amp;rsquo;ailleurs, nous avons célébré hier 59 années sans armée—et bien que je suis contre la violence qu&amp;rsquo;avoir une armée implique habituellement, je dois admettre que j&amp;rsquo;admire les établissements militaires. Après tout, beaucoup d&amp;rsquo;avances modernes sont malheureusement le résultat de la recherche qui d&amp;rsquo;abord a été prévue pour la guerre et je ne nierai pas que deux ou trois mois de discipline martiale ne seraient pas si mauvais pour pas mal de jeunes d&amp;rsquo;aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui.</description></item><item><title>El ejército británico usa controles de Xbox 360 para sus VANTs</title><link>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs-es/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs-es/</guid><description>Vengo de un país que no tiene ejército—de hecho, celebramos ayer 59 años sin ejército—y aunque estoy contra la violencia que tener un ejército implica generalmente, tengo que admitir que admiro a las instituciones militares. Después de todo, muchos avances modernos son desafortunadamente el resultado de la investigación que al principio fue pensada para la guerra y no negaré que un par de meses de disciplina marcial no serían tan malos para muchos jóvenes hoy en día.</description></item><item><title>British Army uses Xbox 360 controllers for UAVs</title><link>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/02/british-army-uses-xbox-360-controllers-for-uavs/</guid><description>I come from a country which has no army—as a matter of fact, yesterday we celebrated 59 army-less years—and although I&amp;rsquo;m against the violence that having an army usually implies, I have to admit that I admire military institutions. After all, many modern advances are unfortunately the result of research which at first was intended for war and I won&amp;rsquo;t deny that a couple of months of martial discipline wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so bad for many of today&amp;rsquo;s youths.</description></item></channel></rss>