<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog Stuff on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/category/blog-stuff/</link><description>Recent content in Blog Stuff on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 07:50:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/category/blog-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Le blog fait peau neuve</title><link>/2011/04/15/le-blog-fait-peau-neuve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 07:50:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/04/15/le-blog-fait-peau-neuve/</guid><description>Je suis le premier à l’avouer, je ne suis pas doué pour faire vivre un blog, mais j’aime le concept, donc je m’acharne !
Des blogs, j’en ai eu depuis des années :
Au début, c’était des pages statiques mises à jour sous Notepad, mais la curiosité m’a poussé à faire un premier essai de génération dynamique en PHP peu de temps après. Evidemment, les fonctionnalités étaient limités—et la sécurité médiocre—donc je suis passé sous Wordpress.</description></item><item><title>C’est la fin de Microsoft Live Spaces</title><link>/2010/09/28/crsquoest-la-fin-de-microsoft-live-spaces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 04:32:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/09/28/crsquoest-la-fin-de-microsoft-live-spaces/</guid><description>C’est ce qu’a été annoncé il y a quelques heures par Dharmesh Mehta, Director of Product Management de Windows Live à TechCrunch Disrupt.
Que deviennent donc tous ces magnifiques blogs hébergés sur la plateforme Live Spaces ?
La présence de Toni Schneider, PDG de Automattic, n’était pas anodine, parce que, comme vous l’aurez deviné, c’est Wordpress.com qui ca prendre la relève.
Les blogs existants seront donc, au choix de l’utilisateur, migrés sur Wordpress.</description></item><item><title>Jake Shimabukuro et son ukulele à TEDx Tokyo</title><link>/2010/05/18/jake-shimabukuro-et-son-ukulele-agrave-tedx-tokyo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 09:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/18/jake-shimabukuro-et-son-ukulele-agrave-tedx-tokyo/</guid><description>J&amp;rsquo;avais déjà entendu Jake Shimabukuro quelque part, mais je n&amp;rsquo;arrive pas à me souvenir où. Je savais qu&amp;rsquo;il était bon, mais cette vidéo enregistrée à TEDx Tokyo m&amp;rsquo;a laissée bouche bée pendant 22 minutes.
Prenez le temps de regarder la vidéo en entier, ça vaut vraiment la peine :
Il joue 3 morceaux :
Un &amp;ldquo;Flamenco ukulele&amp;rdquo; que, je pense, est une composition originale &amp;ldquo;Ave Maria&amp;rdquo; de Schubert, à l&amp;rsquo;ukulele !</description></item><item><title>Où suis-je ? Où vais-je ?</title><link>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 09:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/05/10/ougrave-suisje-ougrave-vaisje/</guid><description>Des questions que je me pose bien plus souvent que je ne le devrais, mais non, ce n’est pas de mes problèmes de mémoire que je voulais parler. La question que l’on m’a posée c’est : où suis-je “virtuellement” ? Je tweete à peine, je ne blogue plus, ni ici ni là …
L’explication est simple ; et double ou triple à la fois. D’une part, si je ne dis rien, c’est probablement parce que je n’ai rien à dire, mais vous savez aussi que souvent quand je n’ai rien à dire je finis par dire quelque chose quand même, donc que se passe-t-il ?</description></item><item><title>Je serais presque célèbre !</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-fr/</guid><description>Il y a quelques semaines, j&amp;rsquo;ai été suivi par un caméraman pendant une journée pour un reportage pour France 24. Je savais que ça allait passer à la télé, sur leur site web et sur YouTube pendant l&amp;rsquo;été et ils m&amp;rsquo;ont dit qu&amp;rsquo;ils me tiendraient informé. Mais ce n&amp;rsquo;est pas comme ça que les choses se passent de nos jours&amp;hellip;
Dimanche dernier, un dimanche matin comme les autres, je me lève à 13h et j&amp;rsquo;ouvre mon PC.</description></item><item><title>¡Ya soy casi famoso!</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-es/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous-es/</guid><description>Hace unas semanas me siguió durante todo un día un camarógrafo para hacer un reportaje para France 24 (un canal de televisión francés). Yo sabía que iba a pasar en la televisión, su página web y en YouTube en algún momento este verano y me dijeron que me mantendrían al tanto. Pero así no es como funcionan las cosas hoy en día&amp;hellip;
El domingo pasado, una mañana dominical como las otras, a eso de la 1 p.</description></item><item><title>I'm almost famous!</title><link>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 19:57:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/01/im-almost-famous/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I was followed around by a cameraman for a piece for France 24 (a French TV station). I knew that it would be broadcast on TV, their web site and on YouTube sometime during the summer and they told me that they&amp;rsquo;d let me know. But that&amp;rsquo;s not how things work nowadays&amp;hellip;
Last Sunday, a regular Sunday morning, I woke up at around 1 p.m. and opened my computer.</description></item><item><title>Thank you for visiting, come back soon...</title><link>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon/</guid><description>I regularly check my blog&amp;rsquo;s stats, more for fun and curiosity than for anything else. I like to check who my knowledge (in a very broad sense of the word) might be going to.
This is a map of recent geographic distribution of my visitors that was very pleasant to see by the way:
Obviously, many of the countries that are green only provided one or two visitors, but still, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Gracias por su visita, espero verlos de nuevo pronto...</title><link>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon-es/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon-es/</guid><description>Regularmente reviso las estadísticas de mi blog, sobre todo por diversión y por curiosidad. Me gusta saber a quién le llegan mis conocimientos (en un sentido amplio de la palabra).
Este es un mapa reciente de la distribución geográfica de mis visitas que me parece muy interesante de hecho:
Obviamente, muchos de los países en verde sólo contribuyeron con una o dos visitas, pero igual, me gusta el mapa&amp;hellip;
Como ya lo dije en el título: gracias por venir, espero que disfruten y que vuelvan pronto ;)</description></item><item><title>Merci d'être venu et au plaisir de vous revoir prochainement...</title><link>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon-fr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 14:21:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/29/thank-you-for-visiting-come-back-soon-fr/</guid><description>Je regarde les statistiques de mon blog régulièrement, plus pour le fun et la curiosité que pour autre chose. J&amp;rsquo;aime bien voir à profite de mes connaissances (au sens très large du terme).
Voilà une carte récente de la distribution géographique de mes visiteurs que je trouve très sympa d&amp;rsquo;ailleurs :
Evidemment, la plupart des pays qui sont en vert n&amp;rsquo;ont contribué qu&amp;rsquo;un ou deux visiteurs, mais c&amp;rsquo;est quand même sympa à voir&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Photos with BillG</title><link>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 12:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</guid><description>As usual these days, there were all sorts of cameras present at yesterday&amp;rsquo;s activity. This is great because I of course couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my own pictures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a selection of pictures that I have received:
Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s me, to his left first and then to his right.
And here are links I&amp;rsquo;ve received/found with pictures of the event. I&amp;rsquo;ll be editing these as I find/get new ones:
G-IT Photos by Séverin Ferrand Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Emmanuel de Taillac Photos by Maxime Gaillard Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Johanna Piou</description></item><item><title>Music in Seoul</title><link>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/18/music-in-seoul/</guid><description>There was one thing I loved about Seoul and it&amp;rsquo;s that, wherever you were, if there was a little green near you, there was music to be heard. Gyongbokgung was not an exception. Indeed, I actually got to see the artists behind the music and one of them was glad to perform before the camera:</description></item><item><title>Imagine Cup 2007 Results, you cannot win every time</title><link>/2007/08/13/imagine-cup-2007-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 02:47:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/08/13/imagine-cup-2007-results/</guid><description>This post is long due, but I guess since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t concern me I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a hurry.
No, I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding. Of course, the most exciting moment of every competition is the announcement of the winners, so here they are, in case you are not interested in the official press release:
Software Design
First place: Thailand — Team 3KC Returns/Project LiveBook! Prachaya Phaisanwiphatpong, Vasan Chienmaneetaweesin, Jatupon Sukkasem, Pathompol Saeng-Uraiporn Second place: Korea — Team En#605/Project Finger Code Lim Chan-kyu, Min Kyoung-hoon, Lim Byoung-su, Jeong Ji-hyeon Third place: Jamaica — Team ICAD/Project CADI Imran Allie, Conroy Smith, Ayson Baxter, Damion Mitchell Embedded Development</description></item><item><title>My Blog - Beta!</title><link>/2007/07/02/my-blog-beta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 11:02:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/02/my-blog-beta/</guid><description>When I announced my new blog last night, I forgot to mention something: I should have added the word &amp;ldquo;Beta&amp;rdquo; somewhere near the logo, because this site is far from being complete. And I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about content, because we all know that a blog is never complete when it comes to content (unless it&amp;rsquo;s closed), I&amp;rsquo;m talking about code!
No, this is not a &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; web site, it&amp;rsquo;s just that the engine I&amp;rsquo;m working on to host this hasn&amp;rsquo;t been finished.</description></item><item><title>Back online!</title><link>/2007/07/01/back-online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/01/back-online/</guid><description>So, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know when this will be true because it will depend on the time the new IP address replicates through DNS, but still, I&amp;rsquo;m back online!
So, my previous host lost most of my data. I will slowly restore/rewrite as much as I can.
For now, enjoy the new look and new engine, of which I will probably be writing in the following weeks as I develop it further with my friend Patrice.</description></item><item><title>I’ve been tagged (prologue)</title><link>/2007/02/28/ive-been-tagged-prologue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 21:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/02/28/ive-been-tagged-prologue/</guid><description>Since Patrice tagged me, I guess it’s my geek duty to share 5 things people don’t know about me with whatever stranger stumbles upon my blog (and the few regular readers.)
I’ll need a moment to think though, because if there are aspects of my life that are not public it’s probably because I like them that way.
There’s a trip to China coming up soon (Saturday), so I’ll have some time to think then.</description></item><item><title>Wow, what a day!</title><link>/2006/11/10/wow-what-a-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2006 13:51:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/11/10/wow-what-a-day/</guid><description>In the good sense of course… Today was a great day! It was a day of discovery, of rediscovery, of new things in general.
So, what’s all the excitement about?, you might wonder. Well, let’s see, more or less in order:
I might be onto a gig in Malaysia, how cool is that?
I was one of the winners of the Trick-or-Treat category in MAKE’s Halloween contest! I get the latest issue of MAKE magazine.</description></item></channel></rss>