<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Table Storage on madd0's tech blog</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/tag/azure-table-storage/</link><description>Recent content in Azure Table Storage on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 12:41:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.madd0.com/tag/azure-table-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accessing Windows Azure Diagnostics Logs With LINQPad</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/02/02/accessing-windows-azure-diagnostics-logs-with-linqpad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 12:41:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/02/02/accessing-windows-azure-diagnostics-logs-with-linqpad/</guid><description>If you are using Windows Azure Diagnostics with the DiagnosticMonitorTraceListener you will most likely have a table in your storage account called WADLogsTable with a ton of data in it. It can be a bit overwhelming.
A colleague and I wanted to get two simple pieces of information: an event&amp;rsquo;s date and the corresponding message. Furthermore, we only wanted events that had happened today. Here&amp;rsquo;s what we came up with using LINQPad and the Azure Storage Driver.</description></item><item><title>LINQPad Driver for Azure Table Storage</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/01/09/linqpad-driver-for-azure-table-storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 15:01:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/01/09/linqpad-driver-for-azure-table-storage/</guid><description>I promise, this is the last you will see on this subject today (from my part, anyway). It&amp;rsquo;s for those who were not online yesterday and/or are in a different time zone and/or didn&amp;rsquo;t see my post from yesterday and/or don&amp;rsquo;t speak French.
Azure Storage Explorer I&amp;rsquo;ve been working quite a bit with Windows Azure lately and particularly with Table Storage. I used to use SQL Server Mangement Studio to work with SQL Server and I found Azure Storage Explorer (screenshot on the left), which is actually pretty good for working with all three storage options: queues, tables and blobs.</description></item><item><title>Driver Azure Table Storage pour LINQPad</title><link>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/01/08/driver-azure-table-storage-pour-linqpad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.madd0.com/2012/01/08/driver-azure-table-storage-pour-linqpad/</guid><description>Vous connaissez LINQPad ? Scott Hanselman le recommande systématiquement dans liste annuelle d’outils pour développeurs. En ce qui me concerne, je m’en sers pratiquement tous les jours—enfin, quand je développe.
À la base, c’est un logiciel qui vous permet d’exécuter des requêtes Linq :
Mais ça permet aussi d’exécuter des bouts de code arbitraires, juste pour voir ce que ça donne :
La fonctionnalité que j’utilise le plus c’est définitivement celle-ci, mais ces derniers temps je travaille de plus en plus avec Windows Azure et notamment Table Storage.</description></item></channel></rss>