<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paris on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tag/paris/</link><description>Recent content in Paris on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 11:42:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tag/paris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paris ouvre ses données publiques</title><link>/2011/02/01/paris-ouvre-ses-donnes-publiques/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 11:42:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/02/01/paris-ouvre-ses-donnes-publiques/</guid><description>C’est sous ce titre accrocheur que la ville de Paris a lancé ce mois-ci son initiative de partage des données publiques, suivant l’exemple d’autres administrations telles que le gouvernement britanique ou encore la Ville de New York.
Cette démarche d&amp;rsquo;ouverture des données publiques s&amp;rsquo;intègre dans une politique globale d&amp;rsquo;innovation ouverte menée par la Ville de Paris depuis 2008, dans laquelle la Ville toute entière devient un terrain d&amp;rsquo;expérimentation, et où les habitants deviennent co-concepteurs des évolutions de leur Ville.</description></item><item><title>Great people meet at La Sorbonne</title><link>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/11/great-people-meet-at-la-sorbonne/</guid><description>A few weeks ago I posted the pictures of the Imagine Cup conference that took place in Paris and during which I had the opportunity to interview Bill Gates.
An event like that was of course filmed and now the videos are also available for online viewing and for download from the web site of Microsoft France.
There are six videos:
French (well, French and Costa Rican :P) finalists from 2007 (French) Bernard Charlès, CEO Dassault Systèmes (French) Ora Ito, Designer (French) Andrew Herbert, Microsoft Research Cambridge (English) Bill Gates, Microsoft Chairman (English) Q&amp;amp;A with Bill Gates (you can see me here again) (English) Click on &amp;ldquo;Voir &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to view the video online or &amp;ldquo;Télécharger&amp;rdquo; to download.</description></item><item><title>Photos with BillG</title><link>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 12:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/30/photos-with-billg/</guid><description>As usual these days, there were all sorts of cameras present at yesterday&amp;rsquo;s activity. This is great because I of course couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my own pictures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a selection of pictures that I have received:
Yep, that&amp;rsquo;s me, to his left first and then to his right.
And here are links I&amp;rsquo;ve received/found with pictures of the event. I&amp;rsquo;ll be editing these as I find/get new ones:
G-IT Photos by Séverin Ferrand Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Emmanuel de Taillac Photos by Maxime Gaillard Photos by Stéphane Rangaya Photos by Johanna Piou</description></item></channel></rss>