<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on madd0's tech blog</title><link>/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on madd0's tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 08:10:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ellen DeGeneres forcée de s’excuser auprès d’Apple</title><link>/2010/05/05/ellen-degeneres-forceacutee-de-srsquoexcuser-aupregraves-drsquoapple/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 08:10:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/05/ellen-degeneres-forceacutee-de-srsquoexcuser-aupregraves-drsquoapple/</guid><description>Ne vous inquiétez pas, je ne risque pas de devenir un blog consacré à Apple, mais les histoires récentes me font tellement halluciner que je ne peux pas ne pas les partager.
Tenez, par exemple, cette vidéo d’Ellen, qui a eu la terrible idée de faire une parodie des pubs iPhone :
Apple lui a demandé de s’excuser ! Parce que, je traduis grossièrement, “elle fait croire que l’utilisation de l’iPhone est difficile” !</description></item><item><title>On Jobs’s thoughts on Flash</title><link>/2010/04/30/on-jobsrsquos-thoughts-on-flash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 07:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/30/on-jobsrsquos-thoughts-on-flash/</guid><description>Yesterday, our favourite black turtleneck-wearing guru published a short essay detailing his Thoughts on Flash, where he details why Adobe’s Flash will never by supported on his iPhones and iPads.
Recommended reading, definitively! It’s just hilarious.
I obviously have to admit that the iPhone, new Macs, etc. have sent Jobs soaring through the stratosphere. Unfortunately, I’m afraid his brain is now lacking oxygen…
Take a look at some of Jobs’s points:</description></item><item><title>Plus de C# sur l’iPhone ?</title><link>/2010/04/09/plus-de-c-sur-lrsquoiphone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 06:41:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/09/plus-de-c-sur-lrsquoiphone/</guid><description>Avec la sortie hier du SDK pour l’iPhone OS 4, Apple surprend les développeurs en modifiant un paragraphe clé dans sa licence d’utilisation. Jusque là le paragraphe 3.3.1. lisait :
3.3.1 — Applications may only use Documented APIs in the manner prescribed by Apple and must not use or call any private APIs.
Formulé de cette manière, ce paragraphe empêche simplement les développeurs d’accéder aux fonctionnalités de l’iPhone qui ne sont pas exposées par les APIs publiques, documentées et donc supportées par Apple.</description></item><item><title>The Simpsons visit the Mapple Store</title><link>/2008/12/01/the-simpsons-visit-the-mapple-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 10:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/12/01/the-simpsons-visit-the-mapple-store/</guid><description>In the latest Simpsons episode, the family visits the new Mapple Store at the mall.
I don’t know how long the video will stay online, but it’s just great!
I had never visited an Apple Store before my trip to London at the beginning of the month, but I found it was really fun; it felt like visiting the HQ of the Church of Scientology for some reason :P
Anyway, enjoy the fist few minutes of perfect Simpsons sarcasm.</description></item><item><title>Perfectamente tonto</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-es/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-es/</guid><description>¡Hay errores que son simplemente demasiado perfectos!
El texto en rojo se traduciría “Perfectamente tonto” en español.
Yo nada digo: Perfecto!</description></item><item><title>Parfaitement con</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-fr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb-fr/</guid><description>Il y a des coquilles qui sont juste trop belles !
Pas besoin de traduire dans cette version, c’est juste beau comme ça.
Je vais me limiter à dire : Parfait !</description></item><item><title>Perfectly dumb</title><link>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 17:34:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/14/perfectly-dumb/</guid><description>Some typos are just beautiful!
The highlighted text would read “Perfectly dumb” or maybe even “Perfectly stupid” in English.
I’ll just say: Perfect!</description></item></channel></rss>